<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Revolution on The Condition of the Republic</title>
    <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/tags/revolution/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Revolution on The Condition of the Republic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 23:01:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aonchiallach.github.io/tags/revolution/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Marx and Revolution</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/marx_revolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/marx_revolution/</guid>
      <description>(A cursory analysis of theories of revolution pre and post Marx. I was asked to write this for a general audience publication but it was spiked for eclecticism.)
Readers of Marx will know that his writings, on the levels of their content, topic and style, can be separated into two distinct categories. First, the polemical journalism marshalling a broad swathe of human history and social change within highly quotable, almost literary turns of phrase, second, the more abstract, scientific (possibly less enjoyable but no less necessary) critiques of political economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Three Stages of the Irish Revolution</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/irish_revolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/irish_revolution/</guid>
      <description>Prelude to the Rising
Thomas Clarke was born in 1858 to an Irish family living in Hampshire in England. His father was in the British army and was briefly stationed in South Africa before the family returned to Dungannon in County Tyrone, where Clarke became involved in the Irish Republican Brotherhood, a secret society founded by the Fenians in 1858 to advance the cause of Irish separatism. Imprisoned for fifteen years for his role in an incendiary bombing campaign in London, Clarke emigrated to the United States, where he re-founded the IRB with Patrick McCartan and Denis McCullough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why ‘Stephen Hero’ is better than ‘A Portrait of the Artist as a Young Man’</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/joyce_stephen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/joyce_stephen/</guid>
      <description>I do not quite believe that Stephen Hero is a better novel than A Portrait of the Artist as a Young Man. Reading Stephen Hero at a significant remove from Portrait convinced me that it could be, for the reason that we get far more frequent and more extensive insights into what Joyce’s actual line on social and national questions might be, but having gone back to Portrait to check I can confirm that the latter is correctly regarded as the better work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Documentaries about the Troubles</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/documentaries_troubles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/documentaries_troubles/</guid>
      <description>Most of these have been ripped off old VHS tapes which are themselves recordings of television broadcasts. The uploaders will have been conscientious enough to edit out the ad breaks, but sometimes they are left in. These are never quite as interesting as you expect them to be; none of them offer a very robust insight into the times in which they were broadcast, they are primarily noteworthy from the point of view of how orange television signals seemed to have been in the eighties and nineties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charlotte Perkins Gilman&#39;s &#39;The Yellow Wallpaper&#39;</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/gilman_yellow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/gilman_yellow/</guid>
      <description>The idea of this story as representing a protagonist subject to a very nineteenth century medical regime of isolation by a domineering husband will be familiar, but I see it more as dealing with the notion of phases of historical development. The walls, gates and labourer’s homes her windows look out onto partaking of the residua of a feudal order, her husband with his reliance on that which is quantifiable, not to mention her own desire being channelled through a wish to make herself useful in gainful labour are all suggestive of the new order of things yet to consolidate themselves, the yellow wallpaper its interior accompaniment.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
