<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Condition of the Republic</title>
    <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Condition of the Republic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 09:11:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aonchiallach.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>George Saunders&#39; &#39;A Swim in a Pond in the Rain&#39;</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/saunders/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/saunders/</guid>
      <description>This book emerges from George Saunders’ experience leading a class in Syracuse University on writing the short story form. The texts which have shaped his understanding, as laid out here, are all Russian. Seven stories from Chekhov, Gogol, Tolstoy and Turgenev appear in the edition, followed by a chapter in which Saunders lays out the lessons it offers.
I have never undertaken an MFA programme but I have attended a couple of creative writing classes both in and outside of a university context.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Karl Marx&#39;s Capital Volume One</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/capital_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/capital_notes/</guid>
      <description>[All page references refer to the unabridged Penguin Edition]
Chapter One: Commodities
The Two Factors of the Commodity
125 The capitalist economy consists of commodities. A commodity is an object of consumption or of production. It satisfies a need and this need is referred to as the commodity’s use-value.
[126 Footnote cites Locke ‘The natural worth of anything consists in its fitness to supply the necessities, or serve the conveniences of human life’]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roger Casement&#39;s Speech from the Dock</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/casement_dock/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 09:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/casement_dock/</guid>
      <description>On 21 April 1916 a German submarine put Roger Casement ashore at Banna Strand in Tralee Bay, County Kerry. For his efforts to procure German arms for the Easter Rising, which would take place three days later, he was arrested on charges of high treason, sabotage and espionage against the Crown.
Casement&amp;rsquo;s trial opened at the Royal Courts of Justice on 26 June 1916. He was found guilty and hanged, one of sixteen Irish men executed in the immediate aftermath of the Rising for their attempts to free their country from the most powerful Empire on the face of the earth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>George Bernard Shaw&#39;s Defense of Roger Casement</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/casement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/casement/</guid>
      <description>On 21 April 1916 a German submarine put Roger Casement ashore at Banna Strand in Tralee Bay, County Kerry. For his efforts to procure German arms for the Easter Rising, which would take place three days later, he was arrested on charges of high treason, sabotage and espionage against the Crown.
Casement&amp;rsquo;s trial opened at the Royal Courts of Justice on 26 June 1916. He was found guilty and hanged, one of sixteen Irish men executed in the immediate aftermath of the Rising for their attempts to free their country from the most powerful Empire on the face of the earth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the JFK Assassination</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/jfk_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/jfk_notes/</guid>
      <description>Scott, Peter Dale. Deep Politics and the Death of JFK. University of California Press, 1996.
4 The Warren Report&amp;rsquo;s representation of Jack Ruby as a loner was clearly false; the FBI went to great lengths to conceal Ruby&amp;rsquo;s connections to organised crime.
38 On November 25 1963, in advance of the Warren Commission being established, its conclusions were published in an AP wire story:
&amp;lsquo;FBI Director J. Edgar Hoover said today all available information indicates that Lee Harvey Oswald acted alone in the assassination of President John F.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tom Nairn and Ireland</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/nairn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 20:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/nairn/</guid>
      <description>A note on terminology: Nairn uses the term &amp;lsquo;Protestants&amp;rsquo; rather than &amp;lsquo;unionists&amp;rsquo; and Ulster rather than &amp;rsquo;the six counties&amp;rsquo; as &amp;lsquo;Ulster&amp;rsquo;
In the opening paragraphs of &amp;lsquo;Northern Ireland: Portent or Relic&amp;rsquo;, a chapter written on Ireland in The Break-up of Britain (1977), Tom Nairn outlines his understanding of the Troubles. From his point of view it is a conflict taking place between two communities. It is separate from the English government, which has no interest in the region, whether strategic, political or ideological.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Politics and Letters</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/podcast/</guid>
      <description>I have a podcast called Politics and Letters in which I talk to writers about their books.
Spotify
RSS
List of Episodes
Fearghal Mac Bhloscaidh &amp;amp; Kerron Ó&amp;rsquo;Luain: The Irish Civil War
Conor McCarthy: Edward Said
Sinéad Kennedy: Repeal the Eighth
Odrán de Bhaldraithe: Neglect in the North of Ireland
Joe Cleary: Outrageous Fortune: Capital and Culture in Modern Ireland
Tom Roseingrave: Frustrated Writer&amp;rsquo;s Group, Vol. 1
Thomas Pynchon&amp;rsquo;s California Novels: The Crying of Lot 49, Vineland and Inherent Vice</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Palestine and the Zionist Entity</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/palestine_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/palestine_notes/</guid>
      <description>Black, Ian. Enemies and Neighbours: Arabs and Jews in Palestine and Israel, 1917 - 2017. Penguin, 2018.
Introduction
12 The Ottomans officially surrendered to the British inside Jerusalem&amp;rsquo;s walled Old City on 9 December 1917.
This ended four centuries of Ottoman imperial rule.
Palestine owed its name to the Romans; to Muslims it was home to Jerusalem&amp;rsquo;s al-Aqsa mosque (the third most sacred site after Mecca and Medina) from where the Prophet Muhammed ascended to heaven.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 11:59:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>This blog is written by Chris Beausang, a writer and critic who was born, and continues to live, in Dublin.
Tunnel of Toads, a novel I wrote about Dublin, is available (here)[https://marrowbone.ie/shop/tunnel-of-toads] from Marrowbone Books.
You can contact me by email: chrisbeausang91 at gmail dot com.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online writing of interest</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/links/</guid>
      <description>Blogs:
An Cáman Solais BLOSC Elliptical Movements New Sinews Red Banner Reflections from Damaged Life WD Clarke&amp;rsquo;s Blog </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/publications/</guid>
      <description>Criticism:
&amp;lsquo;A Brief History of the Theory and Practice of Computational Literary Criticism (1963-2020)&amp;rsquo;, magazén &amp;lsquo;Anois ar teacht an tSamhraidh: Ireland, Colonialism and the Unfinished Revolution [Review]&amp;rsquo; collected in &amp;lsquo;Liberated Texts Vol. 1&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;Diachronic Delta: A computational and dialectical method for analysing literary corpora&amp;rsquo;, Digital Scholarship in the Humanities &amp;lsquo;Modernisms of subversion and dissent&amp;rsquo;, Reflections &amp;rsquo;The Aesthetics of Resistance, Volume II [Review]&amp;rsquo;, Marx &amp;amp; Philosophy Review of Books &amp;lsquo;The Psychology of the Whipped Dog&amp;rsquo;, Demands Most Moderate &amp;lsquo;The Saorstát is a Neo-colony&amp;rsquo;, Rupture Magazine &amp;lsquo;Some means of situating magical realism in contemporary Irish writing&amp;rsquo;, Contemporary Irish Literature Research Network &amp;lsquo;Stalin: Passage to Revolution&amp;rsquo;, Marx &amp;amp; Philosophy Review of Books Fiction:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Narrating Sally Rooney&#39;s &#39;Beautiful World Where Are You?&#39;</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/rooney_beautiful/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/rooney_beautiful/</guid>
      <description>When reading Sally Rooney’s novels I wonder whether or not she is doing the same thing as Joanna Hogg or Harmony Korine, wherein something vacuous and / or vulgar is being represented as a comment on societal vulgarity and vacuousness or whether those being represented, whether upper-class English people or lower-class Americans, are intended to be in and of themselves, sympathetic or interesting. The answer is always both, but I think Beautiful World Where Are You represents a turning point in Rooney’s writing career at which the central point is indeed that we find academically high-achieving and precocious people who attended Trinity College Dublin sympathetic and interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on John Smith&#39;s Imperialism in the Twenty-First Century</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/imperialism_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/imperialism_notes/</guid>
      <description>Chapter One: The Global Commodity
12 Companies based in the West such as Walmart, M&amp;amp;S, Primark have gone to enormous efforts to offshore textile production to Bangladesh in pursuit of lower labour costs. According to trade and financial data however, none of these firms profits or government revenues derived from the labour of the workers who made the goods.
All the goods appear as &amp;lsquo;value-added&amp;rsquo; in the UK and other countries where these goods are consumed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adrian Duncan&#39;s &#39;The Geometer Lobachevsky&#39;</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/duncan_lobachevsky/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/duncan_lobachevsky/</guid>
      <description>A friend of mine described a short story in Adrian Duncan’s 2021 collection Midfield Dynamo as ‘like John McGahern with the humanity stripped out of it’. If you read McGahern’s works in chronological order you can see this humanity begin to edge out the harshness and repetition elsewhere, or at least begin to assert itself more often as a necessary opposite. The last line of McGahern’s last novel is essentially a pitch for a comprehensive transcendence or transformation, a conclusion which I once heard a relative describe as ‘too easy’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Three Stages of the Irish Revolution</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/irish_revolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/irish_revolution/</guid>
      <description>Prelude to the Rising
Thomas Clarke was born in 1858 to an Irish family living in Hampshire in England. His father was in the British army and was briefly stationed in South Africa before the family returned to Dungannon in County Tyrone, where Clarke became involved in the Irish Republican Brotherhood, a secret society founded by the Fenians in 1858 to advance the cause of Irish separatism. Imprisoned for fifteen years for his role in an incendiary bombing campaign in London, Clarke emigrated to the United States, where he re-founded the IRB with Patrick McCartan and Denis McCullough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ireland in the New Left Review</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/ireland_nlr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/ireland_nlr/</guid>
      <description>For the sixty-odd years the New Left Review has been in existence, the country in which the overwhelming majority of its editorial staff and stable of regular contributors were born, grew up and lived has maintained an occupation of six counties on the island of Ireland against the wishes of the Irish people. Irish resistance to partition, which reached an historic high point over a thirty-year period in the lifetime of the journal, became and has remained a rallying point for independence and national liberation movements from South Africa to Palestine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Ireland&#39;s Transition to Capitalism</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/ireland_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/ireland_notes/</guid>
      <description>Coakley, Maurice. Ireland in the World Order: A History of Uneven Development. Pluto Press, 2012
Duffy, Seán, Brian Boru and the Battle of Clontarf. Gill Books, 2014.
McCann, Gerard. Ireland&amp;rsquo;s Economic HIstory: Crisis and Development in the North and South. Pluto Press, 2011.
O&amp;rsquo;Hearn, Denis. The Atlantic Economy: Britain, the US and Ireland. Manchester University Press, 2015.
Ó Siochrú, Micheál. God&amp;rsquo;s Executioner: Oliver Cromwell and the Conquest of Ireland. Faber, 2008</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why ‘Stephen Hero’ is better than ‘A Portrait of the Artist as a Young Man’</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/joyce_stephen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/joyce_stephen/</guid>
      <description>I do not quite believe that Stephen Hero is a better novel than A Portrait of the Artist as a Young Man. Reading Stephen Hero at a significant remove from Portrait convinced me that it could be, for the reason that we get far more frequent and more extensive insights into what Joyce’s actual line on social and national questions might be, but having gone back to Portrait to check I can confirm that the latter is correctly regarded as the better work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Documentaries about the Troubles</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/documentaries_troubles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/documentaries_troubles/</guid>
      <description>Most of these have been ripped off old VHS tapes which are themselves recordings of television broadcasts. The uploaders will have been conscientious enough to edit out the ad breaks, but sometimes they are left in. These are never quite as interesting as you expect them to be; none of them offer a very robust insight into the times in which they were broadcast, they are primarily noteworthy from the point of view of how orange television signals seemed to have been in the eighties and nineties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Production of Style in Eumaeus</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/joyce_eumaeus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/joyce_eumaeus/</guid>
      <description>(Political reading of an episode late into James Joyce&amp;rsquo;s novel Ulysses. It&amp;rsquo;s very academic, I wrote it intending it to form part of the doctoral thesis, but it did not make the final cut.)
‘Eumaeus’ is Ulysses‘ (1922) third last episode and is written in a style manifestly distinct from the rest of the novel. This is due to its functioning, I contend, as a parody of nineteenth century realism, of which someone like Charles Dickens might be said to be a standard-bearer, an author whose works Eumaeus both references and satirises.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the Anderson-Thompson debates</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/anderson_thompson/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/anderson_thompson/</guid>
      <description>Perry Anderson&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;Origins of the Present Crisis&amp;rsquo;
[Page references refer to the essay as it appears in English Questions Verso, 1992]
17 - 18 England experienced the first, most mediated and least pure bourgeois revolution of any major European country during the Civil War of 1640 - 9
20-1 England experienced the first industrial revolution in a period of counter-revolutionary war, producing the earliest proletariat when socialist theory was underdeveloped and an industrial bourgeoisie skewed towards the aristocracy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Karl Marx&#39;s Grundrisse</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/grundrisse_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/grundrisse_notes/</guid>
      <description>[All page references refer to the unabridged Penguin Edition]
Introduction
1. Production, Consumption, Distribution, Exchange (Circulation)
(1) Production
Independent Individuals, Eighteenth-century Ideas
83 Begins with a dismissal of the accounts of political economy provided by bourgeois economists who imagine political economy as functioning in the same way as it is represented in Daniel Defoe&amp;rsquo;s novel Robinson Crusoe, an aesthetic semblance of individual autonomy.
84 Looking back into pre-history the fact of the individual belonging to a far larger social totality becomes more and more obvious; it is only in the eighteenth century, with production and social relations at their most developed point, the creation of &amp;lsquo;civil society&amp;rsquo; that an individual confronts sociality as a means to their own end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Peter Gowan&#39;s &#39;The Global Gamble: Washington&#39;s Faustian Bid for World Dominance&#39;</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/gowan_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/gowan_notes/</guid>
      <description>2: &amp;lsquo;Capital Markets&amp;rsquo;, Financial Systems and the Postwar International Monetary System
The So-called Capital Markets
9 Credit is the lending of money in the expectation that the money will be paid back later along with a bonus or dividend in the form of a rate of interest. This is not necessarily a capitalist mechanism, co-operative societies can issue credit as well as building societies.
10 What makes banks distinct is their use of credit involves the creation of money; banks can be giving overdrafts to everyone in the economy at one time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charlotte Perkins Gilman&#39;s &#39;The Yellow Wallpaper&#39;</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/gilman_yellow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/gilman_yellow/</guid>
      <description>The idea of this story as representing a protagonist subject to a very nineteenth century medical regime of isolation by a domineering husband will be familiar, but I see it more as dealing with the notion of phases of historical development. The walls, gates and labourer’s homes her windows look out onto partaking of the residua of a feudal order, her husband with his reliance on that which is quantifiable, not to mention her own desire being channelled through a wish to make herself useful in gainful labour are all suggestive of the new order of things yet to consolidate themselves, the yellow wallpaper its interior accompaniment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ernest Hemingway&#39;s &#39;The Torrents of Spring&#39; and brand modernism</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/hemingway_modernism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/hemingway_modernism/</guid>
      <description>Ernest Hemingway’s novel Torrents of Springis not very good. An author’s note at its end informs us that it was written in ten days and if this account of its composition is true, it very much shows. The reason I am choosing to inflict this reading experience on myself is because of my PhD research; my stylometric analysis of nineteenth and twentieth century literature, which involves identifying words which are particular to each author, informs me that Torrents of Spring marks a departure from Hemingway’s usual range of expression, away from words like ‘hell’, ‘bottle’, ‘drink’, ‘hit’ and ‘you’re’, to words like ‘wife’, ‘woman’, ‘happiest’, ‘agreed’, and ‘herself’, words Hemingway does not use anywhere else in his oeuvre.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Electoralism in Mike McCormack&#39;s &#39;Solar Bones&#39;</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/solar_bones/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/solar_bones/</guid>
      <description>McCormack’s novel Solar Bones can be regarded as of a piece with the resurgence of Irish neo-modernism, enacted variously by writers such as Anne Enright, Eimear McBride, Sara Baume, Joanna Walsh and Claire Louise-Bennett. The motivations underpinning neo-modernism in other sectors, be it the academy, poetry, performance art and architecture, are highly varied and will not be treated in full here. I would contend that these writers in particular have advanced modernist aesthetics in the name of a feminist agenda, deterritorialising the masculinist stylistic tropes formerly associated with writers such as James Joyce, Samuel Beckett et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Where is our gallant man?&#39;: The Films of Pat Collins</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/pat_collins/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/pat_collins/</guid>
      <description>Seven tourists are standing in an upper floor of a derelict tenement building, now preserved as a museum or installation space. A woman, acting as a pregnant mother in period dress, speaks in a Dublin accent about how she lives like the gentry here, not that the gentry are known for buying second-hand bonnets in Capel Street. As she speaks, coughing can be heard from a neighbouring room, and she wishes her children dead, so as to spare them their long, drawn-out illness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is George Eliot&#39;s &#39;Middlemarch&#39;?</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/eliot_middlemarch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/eliot_middlemarch/</guid>
      <description>Anne Enright once said that every novel could, with minimal damage, be re-titled as Person Gets it Wrong. It is a gesture that would well serve George Eliot’s Middlemarch, as it is a novel primarily concerned with bringing even the most marginal of its characters’ ideals into collision with discommoding contingency. Although, it leaves us with the problem as to what to do with the subtitle, A Study of Provincial Life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joanna Walsh&#39;s &#39;Seed&#39;</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/walsh_seed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/walsh_seed/</guid>
      <description>The first thing one notices about Joanna Walsh’s online novella Seed is the quality of the design. Seed’s aesthetic is very consistent, and was obviously designed with an eye to the material at hand. For all this we have its illustrator Charlotte Hicks to thank, as well as the digital publishing company responsible for designing the platform on which the text is hosted. Seed is optimised for iOS, and, as the site tells us, is probably better viewed there, but it can also be read on a laptop or a PC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chris Morris&#39; Blue Jam Monologues</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/blue_jam/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/blue_jam/</guid>
      <description>Chris Morris’ television show Jam was originally a radio series called Blue Jam, in which five to ten minute ‘sketches’ played out above an ambient soundtrack bed. When it was imported to television, the actors lip-synced to these pre-recordings, intensifying the surreal effect that the show gave off. Jam is subversive, hilarious, absurd and if you’ve never seen it, I’d advise you to keep it that way. Every episode contains at least one thing that is one of the worst things I’ve ever seen, let alone the worst thing I’ve ever seen in show that it supposedly a comedy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Will Self&#39;s Umbrella and post-modern modernity</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/self_umbrella/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/self_umbrella/</guid>
      <description>As has been repeated in any number of the literary outlets which give Will Self column inches, Self has thumbed his nose at the British literary establishment, readers and writers alike, by returning to the ground zero of avant-garde prose writing in his trilogy of Umbrella, Shark and the forthcoming Phone. I held off reading Umbrella for some time, for the same reason that one generally doesn’t read a novel written by one of the authors that one might rate highly, sensing in advance that it will be in some way a disappointment, particularly when said author has set themselves the task of re-invigorating an dormant genre in which one is steeped in, on a semi-professional basis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dylan Moran&#39;s Radio Play, Flann O&#39;Brien and Samuel Beckett</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/moran_beckett/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/moran_beckett/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been a fan of Dylan Moran’s stand-up for as far back as I can remember, since I saw his first stand-up special Monster. I think I was about twelve, and Moran’s misanthropic and depressive whimsy got lodged deep into my world view, and influenced me to try stand-up the few times that I did, aswell as slur the way I speak infinitesimally. I’m not sure if the way I speak now is my actual voice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Garrett Phelan&#39;s Black Brain Radio</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/black_brain/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/black_brain/</guid>
      <description>I really like Arts Tonight on RTÉ. Its quiet pace, insider baseball language and uncompromising commitment to taking a deliberate, intellectual approach to the arts would be easy to parody, but because of its informativeness and tendency to source academics for its panels, it is among the best arts programmes in radio, and I mean the best from both RTÉ and the BBC. I find that the BBC, In Our Time aside, too often goes in for either Today Programme ebullience, in demanding straightforward-one-word, no-nonsense answers to weighty abstract questions or a whimsically boisterous tone, in pursuit of an imagined layman.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
