<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Condition of the Republic</title>
    <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Condition of the Republic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 23:01:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aonchiallach.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Marx and Revolution</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/marx_revolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/marx_revolution/</guid>
      <description>(A cursory analysis of theories of revolution pre and post Marx. I was asked to write this for a general audience publication but it was spiked for eclecticism.)
Readers of Marx will know that his writings, on the levels of their content, topic and style, can be separated into two distinct categories. First, the polemical journalism marshalling a broad swathe of human history and social change within highly quotable, almost literary turns of phrase, second, the more abstract, scientific (possibly less enjoyable but no less necessary) critiques of political economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 11:59:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>This blog is written by Chris Beausang, a writer and critic who was born, and continues to live, in Dublin.
You can contact me by email: chrisbeausang91 at gmail dot com.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online writing of interest</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/links/</guid>
      <description>Blogs:
An Cáman Solais BLOSC Elliptical Movements New Sinews WD Clarke&amp;rsquo;s Blog </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcasts on which I have spoken</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/podcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/podcasts/</guid>
      <description>Podcasts on which I have appeared:
&amp;lsquo;&amp;lsquo;Anois ar teacht an tSamhraidh: Ireland, Colonialism and the Unfinished Revolution:&amp;rsquo;, Rupture Radio &amp;lsquo;James Connolly and Irish anti-colonial resistance, Part 1&amp;rsquo;, The East is a Podcast James Connolly and Irish anti-colonial resistance, Part 2, The East is a Podcast Sex and Socialism: Is there a &amp;lsquo;political turn in contemporary Irish fiction?, Maynooth University The Saorstát is a Neo-colony, Rupture Magazine &amp;lsquo;The Troubles and the Irish Question, Part 1&amp;rsquo;, The East is a Podcast The Troubles and the Irish Question, Part 2, The East is a Podcast </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/publications/</guid>
      <description>Print and online publications:
&amp;lsquo;1980&amp;rsquo;, New Sinews &amp;lsquo;Anois ar teacht an tSamhraidh;: Ireland, Colonialism and the Unfinished Revolution&amp;rsquo;, book review collected in [Liberated Texts Vol.] 1(https://www.ebb-magazine.com/books/p/liberated-texts-vol-1) &amp;lsquo;Diachronic Delta: A computational and dialectical method for analysing literary corpora&amp;rsquo;, Digital Scholarship in the Humanities &amp;lsquo;Paddy Likes to Know&amp;rsquo;, short story collected in The Globe and Scales &amp;lsquo;She Flies Far From the Land&amp;rsquo;, Banshee [&amp;lsquo;Signal&amp;rsquo;], a self-published zine &amp;lsquo;Three Glimpses of Someone Much Better than You Are at Doing the Thing That You Hate Doing the Least&amp;rsquo;, Belfield Literary Review </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Narrating Sally Rooney&#39;s &#39;Beautiful World Where Are You?&#39;</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/rooney_beautiful/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/rooney_beautiful/</guid>
      <description>When reading Sally Rooney’s novels I wonder whether or not she is doing the same thing as Joanna Hogg or Harmony Korine, wherein something vacuous and / or vulgar is being represented as a comment on societal vulgarity and vacuousness or whether those being represented, whether upper-class English people or lower-class Americans, are intended to be in and of themselves, sympathetic or interesting. The answer is always both, but I think Beautiful World Where Are You represents a turning point in Rooney’s writing career at which the central point is indeed that we find academically high-achieving and precocious people who attended Trinity College Dublin sympathetic and interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adrian Duncan&#39;s &#39;The Geometer Lobachevsky&#39;</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/duncan_lobachevsky/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/duncan_lobachevsky/</guid>
      <description>A friend of mine described a short story in Adrian Duncan’s 2021 collection Midfield Dynamo as ‘like John McGahern with the humanity stripped out of it’. If you read McGahern’s works in chronological order you can see this humanity begin to edge out the harshness and repetition elsewhere, or at least begin to assert itself more often as a necessary opposite. The last line of McGahern’s last novel is essentially a pitch for a comprehensive transcendence or transformation, a conclusion which I once heard a relative describe as ‘too easy’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Three Stages of the Irish Revolution</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/irish_revolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/irish_revolution/</guid>
      <description>Prelude to the Rising
Thomas Clarke was born in 1858 to an Irish family living in Hampshire in England. His father was in the British army and was briefly stationed in South Africa before the family returned to Dungannon in County Tyrone, where Clarke became involved in the Irish Republican Brotherhood, a secret society founded by the Fenians in 1858 to advance the cause of Irish separatism. Imprisoned for fifteen years for his role in an incendiary bombing campaign in London, Clarke emigrated to the United States, where he re-founded the IRB with Patrick McCartan and Denis McCullough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ireland in the New Left Review</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/ireland_nlr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/ireland_nlr/</guid>
      <description>For the sixty-odd years the New Left Review has been in existence, the country in which the overwhelming majority of its editorial staff and stable of regular contributors were born, grew up and lived has maintained an occupation of six counties on the island of Ireland against the wishes of the Irish people. Irish resistance to partition, which reached an historic high point over a thirty-year period in the lifetime of the journal, became and has remained a rallying point for independence and national liberation movements from South Africa to Palestine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why ‘Stephen Hero’ is better than ‘A Portrait of the Artist as a Young Man’</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/joyce_stephen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/joyce_stephen/</guid>
      <description>I do not quite believe that Stephen Hero is a better novel than A Portrait of the Artist as a Young Man. Reading Stephen Hero at a significant remove from Portrait convinced me that it could be, for the reason that we get far more frequent and more extensive insights into what Joyce’s actual line on social and national questions might be, but having gone back to Portrait to check I can confirm that the latter is correctly regarded as the better work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Documentaries about the Troubles</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/documentaries_troubles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/documentaries_troubles/</guid>
      <description>Most of these have been ripped off old VHS tapes which are themselves recordings of television broadcasts. The uploaders will have been conscientious enough to edit out the ad breaks, but sometimes they are left in. These are never quite as interesting as you expect them to be; none of them offer a very robust insight into the times in which they were broadcast, they are primarily noteworthy from the point of view of how orange television signals seemed to have been in the eighties and nineties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Production of Style in Eumaeus</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/joyce_eumaeus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/joyce_eumaeus/</guid>
      <description>(Political reading of an episode late into James Joyce&amp;rsquo;s novel Ulysses. It&amp;rsquo;s very academic, I wrote it intending it to form part of the doctoral thesis, but it did not make the final cut.)
‘Eumaeus’ is Ulysses‘ (1922) third last episode and is written in a style manifestly distinct from the rest of the novel. This is due to its functioning, I contend, as a parody of nineteenth century realism, of which someone like Charles Dickens might be said to be a standard-bearer, an author whose works Eumaeus both references and satirises.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charlotte Perkins Gilman&#39;s &#39;The Yellow Wallpaper&#39;</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/gilman_yellow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/gilman_yellow/</guid>
      <description>The idea of this story as representing a protagonist subject to a very nineteenth century medical regime of isolation by a domineering husband will be familiar, but I see it more as dealing with the notion of phases of historical development. The walls, gates and labourer’s homes her windows look out onto partaking of the residua of a feudal order, her husband with his reliance on that which is quantifiable, not to mention her own desire being channelled through a wish to make herself useful in gainful labour are all suggestive of the new order of things yet to consolidate themselves, the yellow wallpaper its interior accompaniment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ernest Hemingway&#39;s &#39;The Torrents of Spring&#39; and brand modernism</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/hemingway_modernism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/hemingway_modernism/</guid>
      <description>Ernest Hemingway’s novel Torrents of Springis not very good. An author’s note at its end informs us that it was written in ten days and if this account of its composition is true, it very much shows. The reason I am choosing to inflict this reading experience on myself is because of my PhD research; my stylometric analysis of nineteenth and twentieth century literature, which involves identifying words which are particular to each author, informs me that Torrents of Spring marks a departure from Hemingway’s usual range of expression, away from words like ‘hell’, ‘bottle’, ‘drink’, ‘hit’ and ‘you’re’, to words like ‘wife’, ‘woman’, ‘happiest’, ‘agreed’, and ‘herself’, words Hemingway does not use anywhere else in his oeuvre.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
