<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Modernism on The Condition of the Republic</title>
    <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/tags/modernism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Modernism on The Condition of the Republic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 23:01:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aonchiallach.github.io/tags/modernism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Charlotte Perkins Gilman&#39;s &#39;The Yellow Wallpaper&#39;</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/gilman_yellow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/gilman_yellow/</guid>
      <description>The idea of this story as representing a protagonist subject to a very nineteenth century medical regime of isolation by a domineering husband will be familiar, but I see it more as dealing with the notion of phases of historical development. The walls, gates and labourer’s homes her windows look out onto partaking of the residua of a feudal order, her husband with his reliance on that which is quantifiable, not to mention her own desire being channelled through a wish to make herself useful in gainful labour are all suggestive of the new order of things yet to consolidate themselves, the yellow wallpaper its interior accompaniment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ernest Hemingway&#39;s &#39;The Torrents of Spring&#39; and brand modernism</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/hemingway_modernism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/hemingway_modernism/</guid>
      <description>Ernest Hemingway’s novel Torrents of Springis not very good. An author’s note at its end informs us that it was written in ten days and if this account of its composition is true, it very much shows. The reason I am choosing to inflict this reading experience on myself is because of my PhD research; my stylometric analysis of nineteenth and twentieth century literature, which involves identifying words which are particular to each author, informs me that Torrents of Spring marks a departure from Hemingway’s usual range of expression, away from words like ‘hell’, ‘bottle’, ‘drink’, ‘hit’ and ‘you’re’, to words like ‘wife’, ‘woman’, ‘happiest’, ‘agreed’, and ‘herself’, words Hemingway does not use anywhere else in his oeuvre.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
