<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Marx on The Condition of the Republic</title>
    <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/tags/marx/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Marx on The Condition of the Republic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 09:11:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aonchiallach.github.io/tags/marx/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Karl Marx&#39;s Capital Volume One</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/capital_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/capital_notes/</guid>
      <description>[All page references refer to the unabridged Penguin Edition]
Chapter One: Commodities
The Two Factors of the Commodity
125 The capitalist economy consists of commodities. A commodity is an object of consumption or of production. It satisfies a need and this need is referred to as the commodity’s use-value.
[126 Footnote cites Locke ‘The natural worth of anything consists in its fitness to supply the necessities, or serve the conveniences of human life’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marx and Revolution</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/marx_revolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/marx_revolution/</guid>
      <description>Readers of Marx will know that his writings, on the levels of their content, topic and style, can be separated into two distinct categories. First, the polemical journalism marshalling a broad swathe of human history and social change within highly quotable, almost literary turns of phrase, second, the more abstract, scientific (possibly less enjoyable but no less necessary) critiques of political economy.
This is of course not to suggest that Marx’s writings on current affairs are devoid of serious analysis, nor that works such as Capital are free from spleen.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
