<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Communism on The Condition of the Republic</title>
    <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/tags/communism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Communism on The Condition of the Republic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 09:11:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aonchiallach.github.io/tags/communism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Karl Marx&#39;s Capital Volume One</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/capital_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/capital_notes/</guid>
      <description>[All page references refer to the unabridged Penguin Edition]
Chapter One: Commodities
The Two Factors of the Commodity
125 The capitalist economy consists of commodities. A commodity is an object of consumption or of production. It satisfies a need and this need is referred to as the commodity’s use-value.
[126 Footnote cites Locke ‘The natural worth of anything consists in its fitness to supply the necessities, or serve the conveniences of human life’]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Karl Marx&#39;s Grundrisse</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/grundrisse_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/grundrisse_notes/</guid>
      <description>[All page references refer to the unabridged Penguin Edition]
Introduction
1. Production, Consumption, Distribution, Exchange (Circulation)
(1) Production
Independent Individuals, Eighteenth-century Ideas
83 Begins with a dismissal of the accounts of political economy provided by bourgeois economists who imagine political economy as functioning in the same way as it is represented in Daniel Defoe&amp;rsquo;s novel Robinson Crusoe, as though its basis is the autonomy of the individual.
84 Looking at history the fact that the individual belongs to a far larger social totality is obvious; it is only in the eighteenth century, when production and social relations reach an advanced stage that civil society arises and individuals begin to confront sociality as a means to their own end.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
