<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Marx on The Condition of the Republic</title>
    <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/tags/marx/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Marx on The Condition of the Republic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 09:11:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aonchiallach.github.io/tags/marx/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Karl Marx&#39;s Capital Volume One</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/capital_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/capital_notes/</guid>
      <description>[All page references refer to the unabridged Penguin Edition]
Chapter One: Commodities
The Two Factors of the Commodity
125 The capitalist economy consists of commodities. A commodity is an object of consumption or of production. It satisfies a need and this need is referred to as the commodity’s use-value.
[126 Footnote cites Locke ‘The natural worth of anything consists in its fitness to supply the necessities, or serve the conveniences of human life’]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marx and Revolution</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/marx_revolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/marx_revolution/</guid>
      <description>Readers of Marx will know that his writings, on the levels of their content, topic and style, can be separated into two distinct categories. First, the polemical journalism marshalling a broad swathe of human history and social change within highly quotable, almost literary turns of phrase, second, the more abstract, scientific (possibly less enjoyable but no less necessary) critiques of political economy.
This is of course not to suggest that Marx’s writings on current affairs are devoid of serious analysis, nor that works such as Capital are free from spleen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on John Smith&#39;s Imperialism in the Twenty-First Century</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/imperialism_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/imperialism_notes/</guid>
      <description>Chapter One: The Global Commodity
12 Companies based in the West such as Walmart, M&amp;amp;S, Primark have gone to enormous efforts to offshore textile production to Bangladesh in pursuit of lower labour costs. According to trade and financial data however, none of these firms profits or government revenues derived from the labour of the workers who made the goods.
All the goods appear as &amp;lsquo;value-added&amp;rsquo; in the UK and other countries where these goods are consumed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Peter Gowan&#39;s &#39;The Global Gamble: Washington&#39;s Faustian Bid for World Dominance&#39;</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/gowan_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/gowan_notes/</guid>
      <description>2: &amp;lsquo;Capital Markets&amp;rsquo;, Financial Systems and the Postwar International Monetary System
The So-called Capital Markets
9 Credit is the lending of money in the expectation that the money will be paid back later along with a bonus or dividend in the form of a rate of interest. This is not necessarily a capitalist mechanism, co-operative societies can issue credit as well as building societies.
10 What makes banks distinct is their use of credit involves the creation of money; banks can be giving overdrafts to everyone in the economy at one time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
