<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Imperialism on The Condition of the Republic</title>
    <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/tags/imperialism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Imperialism on The Condition of the Republic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 09:11:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aonchiallach.github.io/tags/imperialism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Palestine and the Zionist Entity</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/palestine_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/palestine_notes/</guid>
      <description>Black, Ian. Enemies and Neighbours: Arabs and Jews in Palestine and Israel, 1917 - 2017. Penguin, 2018.
Introduction
12 The Ottomans officially surrendered to the British inside Jerusalem&amp;rsquo;s walled Old City on 9 December 1917.
This ended four centuries of Ottoman imperial rule.
Palestine owed its name to the Romans; to Muslims it was home to Jerusalem&amp;rsquo;s al-Aqsa mosque (the third most sacred site after Mecca and Medina) from where the Prophet Muhammed ascended to heaven.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on John Smith&#39;s Imperialism in the Twenty-First Century</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/imperialism_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/imperialism_notes/</guid>
      <description>Chapter One: The Global Commodity
12 Companies based in the West such as Walmart, M&amp;amp;S, Primark have gone to enormous efforts to offshore textile production to Bangladesh in pursuit of lower labour costs. According to trade and financial data however, none of these firms profits or government revenues derived from the labour of the workers who made the goods.
All the goods appear as &amp;lsquo;value-added&amp;rsquo; in the UK and other countries where these goods are consumed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Ireland&#39;s Transition to Capitalism</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/ireland_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/ireland_notes/</guid>
      <description>Coakley, Maurice. Ireland in the World Order: A History of Uneven Development. Pluto Press, 2012
Duffy, Seán, Brian Boru and the Battle of Clontarf. Gill Books, 2014.
McCann, Gerard. Ireland&amp;rsquo;s Economic HIstory: Crisis and Development in the North and South. Pluto Press, 2011.
O&amp;rsquo;Hearn, Denis. The Atlantic Economy: Britain, the US and Ireland. Manchester University Press, 2015.
Ó Siochrú, Micheál. God&amp;rsquo;s Executioner: Oliver Cromwell and the Conquest of Ireland. Faber, 2008</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Peter Gowan&#39;s &#39;The Global Gamble: Washington&#39;s Faustian Bid for World Dominance&#39;</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/gowan_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/gowan_notes/</guid>
      <description>2: &amp;lsquo;Capital Markets&amp;rsquo;, Financial Systems and the Postwar International Monetary System
The So-called Capital Markets
9 Credit is the lending of money in the expectation that the money will be paid back later along with a bonus or dividend in the form of a rate of interest. This is not necessarily a capitalist mechanism, co-operative societies can issue credit as well as building societies.
10 What makes banks distinct is their use of credit involves the creation of money; banks can be giving overdrafts to everyone in the economy at one time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
