<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Imperialism on The Condition of the Republic</title>
    <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/tags/imperialism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Imperialism on The Condition of the Republic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 09:11:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aonchiallach.github.io/tags/imperialism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Notes on John Smith&#39;s Imperialism in the Twenty-First Century</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/smith_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/smith_notes/</guid>
      <description>Chapter One: The Global Commodity
12 Companies based in the West such as Walmart, M&amp;amp;S, Primark have gone to enormous efforts to offshore textile production to Bangladesh in pursuit of lower labour costs. According to trade and financial data however, none of these firms profits or government revenues derived from the labour of the workers who made the goods.
All the goods appear as &amp;lsquo;value-added&amp;rsquo; in the UK and other countries where these goods are consumed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Peter Gowan&#39;s The Global Gamble</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/global_gamble/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/global_gamble/</guid>
      <description>Capital Markets, Financial Systems and the Postwar International Monetary System
The So-called Capital Markets
8 The global capital markets through which trillions of dollars pass every day should be viewed as a charge on the productive system rather than a source of funds for new production.
9 Credit is lending money to people on the understanding that they will pay the money back later along with something extra, usually in the form of a rate of interest.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
