<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Modernism on The Condition of the Republic</title>
    <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/tags/modernism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Modernism on The Condition of the Republic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 23:01:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aonchiallach.github.io/tags/modernism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Charlotte Perkins Gilman&#39;s &#39;The Yellow Wallpaper&#39;</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/gilman_yellow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/gilman_yellow/</guid>
      <description>The idea of this story as representing a protagonist subject to a very nineteenth century medical regime of isolation by a domineering husband will be familiar, but I see it more as dealing with the notion of phases of historical development. The walls, gates and labourer’s homes her windows look out onto partaking of the residua of a feudal order, her husband with his reliance on that which is quantifiable, not to mention her own desire being channelled through a wish to make herself useful in gainful labour are all suggestive of the new order of things yet to consolidate themselves, the yellow wallpaper its interior accompaniment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ernest Hemingway&#39;s &#39;The Torrents of Spring&#39; and brand modernism</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/hemingway_modernism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/hemingway_modernism/</guid>
      <description>Ernest Hemingway’s novel Torrents of Springis not very good. An author’s note at its end informs us that it was written in ten days and if this account of its composition is true, it very much shows. The reason I am choosing to inflict this reading experience on myself is because of my PhD research; my stylometric analysis of nineteenth and twentieth century literature, which involves identifying words which are particular to each author, informs me that Torrents of Spring marks a departure from Hemingway’s usual range of expression, away from words like ‘hell’, ‘bottle’, ‘drink’, ‘hit’ and ‘you’re’, to words like ‘wife’, ‘woman’, ‘happiest’, ‘agreed’, and ‘herself’, words Hemingway does not use anywhere else in his oeuvre.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Electoralism in Mike McCormack&#39;s &#39;Solar Bones&#39;</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/solar_bones/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/solar_bones/</guid>
      <description>McCormack’s novel Solar Bones can be regarded as of a piece with the resurgence of Irish neo-modernism, enacted variously by writers such as Anne Enright, Eimear McBride, Sara Baume, Joanna Walsh and Claire Louise-Bennett. The motivations underpinning neo-modernism in other sectors, be it the academy, poetry, performance art and architecture, are highly varied and will not be treated in full here. I would contend that these writers in particular have advanced modernist aesthetics in the name of a feminist agenda, deterritorialising the masculinist stylistic tropes formerly associated with writers such as James Joyce, Samuel Beckett et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Will Self&#39;s Umbrella and post-modern modernity</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/self_umbrella/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/self_umbrella/</guid>
      <description>As has been repeated in any number of the literary outlets which give Will Self column inches, Self has thumbed his nose at the British literary establishment, readers and writers alike, by returning to the ground zero of avant-garde prose writing in his trilogy of Umbrella, Shark and the forthcoming Phone. I held off reading Umbrella for some time, for the same reason that one generally doesn’t read a novel written by one of the authors that one might rate highly, sensing in advance that it will be in some way a disappointment, particularly when said author has set themselves the task of re-invigorating an dormant genre in which one is steeped in, on a semi-professional basis.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
