<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Capitalism on The Condition of the Republic</title>
    <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/tags/capitalism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Capitalism on The Condition of the Republic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 09:11:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aonchiallach.github.io/tags/capitalism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Karl Marx&#39;s Grundrisse</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/grundrisse_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/grundrisse_notes/</guid>
      <description>[All page references refer to the unabridged Penguin Edition]
Introduction
1. Production, Consumption, Distribution, Exchange (Circulation)
(1) Production
Independent Individuals, Eighteenth-century Ideas
83 Begins with a dismissal of the accounts of political economy provided by bourgeois economists who imagine political economy as functioning in the same way as it is represented in Daniel Defoe&amp;rsquo;s novel Robinson Crusoe, an aesthetic semblance of individual autonomy.
84 Looking back into pre-history the fact of the individual belonging to a far larger social totality becomes more and more obvious; it is only in the eighteenth century, with production and social relations at their most developed point, the creation of &amp;lsquo;civil society&amp;rsquo; that an individual confronts sociality as a means to their own end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Karl Marx&#39;s Capital Volume One</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/capital_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/capital_notes/</guid>
      <description>[All page references refer to the unabridged Penguin Edition]
Chapter One: Commodities
The Two Factors of the Commodity
125 The capitalist economy consists of commodities. A commodity is an object of consumption or of production. It satisfies a need and this need is referred to as the commodity’s use-value.
[126 Footnote cites Locke ‘The natural worth of anything consists in its fitness to supply the necessities, or serve the conveniences of human life’]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on John Smith&#39;s Imperialism in the Twenty-First Century</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/imperialism_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/imperialism_notes/</guid>
      <description>Chapter One: The Global Commodity
12 Companies based in the West such as Walmart, M&amp;amp;S, Primark have gone to enormous efforts to offshore textile production to Bangladesh in pursuit of lower labour costs. According to trade and financial data however, none of these firms profits or government revenues derived from the labour of the workers who made the goods.
All the goods appear as &amp;lsquo;value-added&amp;rsquo; in the UK and other countries where these goods are consumed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Ireland&#39;s Transition to Capitalism</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/ireland_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/ireland_notes/</guid>
      <description>Coakley, Maurice. Ireland in the World Order: A History of Uneven Development. Pluto Press, 2012
6 The socio-political evolution of Leinster, Munster and England in the eleventh and twelfth centuries seem similar; both were conquered by French-speaking knights who established a seignoral social order and manorial economy based on intensive arable agriculture as opposed to pastoral husbandry, an extensive trade network and urban development, consolidating the market towns the Vikings had establishing along the coast under the English monarch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Peter Gowan&#39;s &#39;The Global Gamble: Washington&#39;s Faustian Bid for World Dominance&#39;</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/gowan_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/gowan_notes/</guid>
      <description>2: &amp;lsquo;Capital Markets&amp;rsquo;, Financial Systems and the Postwar International Monetary System
The So-called Capital Markets
9 Credit is the lending of money in the expectation that the money will be paid back later along with a bonus or dividend in the form of a rate of interest. This is not necessarily a capitalist mechanism, co-operative societies can issue credit as well as building societies.
10 What makes banks distinct is their use of credit involves the creation of money; banks can be giving overdrafts to everyone in the economy at one time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Peter Gowan&#39;s The Global Gamble</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/global_gamble/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/global_gamble/</guid>
      <description>Capital Markets, Financial Systems and the Postwar International Monetary System
The So-called Capital Markets
8 The global capital markets through which trillions of dollars pass every day should be viewed as a charge on the productive system rather than a source of funds for new production.
9 Credit is lending money to people on the understanding that they will pay the money back later along with something extra, usually in the form of a rate of interest.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
