<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Joyce on The Condition of the Republic</title>
    <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/tags/joyce/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Joyce on The Condition of the Republic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 23:01:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aonchiallach.github.io/tags/joyce/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why ‘Stephen Hero’ is better than ‘A Portrait of the Artist as a Young Man’</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/joyce_stephen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/joyce_stephen/</guid>
      <description>I do not quite believe that Stephen Hero is a better novel than A Portrait of the Artist as a Young Man. Reading Stephen Hero at a significant remove from Portrait convinced me that it could be, for the reason that we get far more frequent and more extensive insights into what Joyce’s actual line on social and national questions might be, but having gone back to Portrait to check I can confirm that the latter is correctly regarded as the better work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Production of Style in Eumaeus</title>
      <link>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/joyce_eumaeus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonchiallach.github.io/posts/joyce_eumaeus/</guid>
      <description>(Political reading of an episode late into James Joyce&amp;rsquo;s novel Ulysses. It&amp;rsquo;s very academic, I wrote it intending it to form part of the doctoral thesis, but it did not make the final cut.)
‘Eumaeus’ is Ulysses‘ (1922) third last episode and is written in a style manifestly distinct from the rest of the novel. This is due to its functioning, I contend, as a parody of nineteenth century realism, of which someone like Charles Dickens might be said to be a standard-bearer, an author whose works Eumaeus both references and satirises.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
